VICTOR SANAVIA

E-mail: vsanaviaf@pm.me www.linkedin.com/in/vsanavia

SUMMARY

Open for remote work.

Senior professional with experience on sales management and technical customer facing roles for cloud, security and development solutions. I'm able to leverage my cloud and development knowledge to create solutions that deliver satisfaction for my customer. Deep understanding of Cloud environment in Latin America.

JOB EXPERIENCE

Independent Advisor: Jan 2021 - Current

Lima, Peru

- Advising partners on business plans focused on recurring revenue products, mainly related to cloud based services and software.
- Planning and deploying a cloud based platform for a reputation based product, mainly using Kafka streams and managed containers on Google Cloud Run.
- Providing cost analysis of cloud architectures and optimizations based on customers' budgets and requirements.

Virtual Sales Account Manager – Cisco Systems, Inc.: Oct 2018 – Dec 2020 Lima, Peru

- Build-up of pipeline on (SMB) accounts with low penetration using social media, cold calling
 and website analytics. Identifying key personas, demand generation via social media and
 managing relationship between customers and partners.
- Leading extended team to increase revenue 110% YoY on commercial accounts on my territory.
- Increasing penetration of software based solutions (Cloud, Security, Datacenter; approximately 40%) for accounts on my territory.

Business Development Manager – Sonda del Peru: May 2017 – July 2018 Lima, Peru

- Working as Point-of-Contact with Cisco to ensure sales quotas are met. This involves
 creating joint marketing plans, development of innovative software based product offerings
 (UC as a Service, UCS, etc.) and day-to-day communications with Cisco sales.
- Engaging medium accounts to increase Sonda's wallet penetration on the Peruvian IT enterprise market.
- Creation of strategy based on BI dashboards to evaluate Pipeline/Forecast behavior. This
 information helped Sonda's leadership team on qualifying sales execution and drive
 continuous improvement on business engagements.

Technical Account Manager – Anida Consultores: Nov 2016 – Apr 2017 Lima, Peru

- Develop and position new service offerings for large service provider, including detailed business plans and creation of marketing assets for service provider sales and presales.
- Explain benefits of observability solutions delivered by integration of open source and commercial software

 Architect APM solution for healthcare mobile application (including instrumentation deployment strategy, threshold identification and reporting)

Sales Engineer – Hewlett Packard Enterprise HPE Software: Jul 2015 - Oct 2016 Lima, Peru

- Serving as technical advisor for complex Cloud and Automation opportunities across Latin America. Communicating cloud strategy to executives of key accounts.
- Develop strategies for customers regarding cloud services architectures and automation deployment.
- Deployment of analytics platform on service provider accounts to exploit Machine Learning to anticipate/forecast failures.
- Architect continuous delivery testing practices that encompass service virtualization, performance and functional testing for development environments.

Sales Engineer – Hewlett-Packard HP Software.: Feb 2013 – Jun 2015 Caracas, Venezuela

- Leading presales technical fulfillment of HP Software Enterprise Licensing Agreements for large financial institutions and Service Providers.
- Providing architectural guidelines for complex technical engagements for opportunities on MCA region.

Sales Engineer – Hewlett-Packard HP Networking: Aug 2010 – Jan 2013 Caracas, Venezuela

- Responsible for starting business operation for HP Networking on the Venezuelan market. Consistent revenue growth of 30% YoY over the time period.
- Led standardization initiative with SP to include HP Networking as Customer Premises Equipment.

Technical Consultant - Sincor (Joint Venture Total/PDVSA/Statoil): Oct 2001 - Dec 2007

- Design and operate enterprise network including WAN, LAN and remote access. Ensure SLO were met using available resources.
- Rearchitect OT network to meet 99.995% yearly availability goal.
- Develop enterprise security policies and continuously adapt them to meet new business requirements and potential weaknesses/threats.

EDUCATION

1999 - Bachelor of Engineering, Electronic Engineer, Universidad Simón Bolivar, Venezuela

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Solutions Architect Associate, ID XQDTKQKJCNFE179C, April 2021
- TOGAF 9 Foundation, License Number 100611 October 2014